Welcome to our training on how to set up a coupon.
You can set up coupons from the Coupons dashboard in Seller Central.
To access the Coupons dashboard, one, sign in to your Seller Central account.
Two, click the menu icon in the top left corner of Seller Central.
Three, hover over the advertising section and select coupons.
Four, if this is your first time setting up a coupon, you'll arrive at a page providing more information
about them.
Review it and then click the create your first coupon button.
If you've set up a coupon before, you'll arrive at your Coupons dashboard automatically.
You'll see any coupons you've already submitted and can filter them by status.
This is also where you'll edit or deactivate your coupons,
but keep in mind that you can't make these changes within approximately six hours of a coupon's
start time.
We use this time to make sure your coupon offers value to Amazon customers.
Follow these steps to create your coupon.
One, click the create a new coupon button.
Two, search for a product by its stockkeeping unit or SKU.
You can also search for it by its Amazon standard identification number or ASIN.
Three, click go and select add to coupon.
You can add up to 200 ASINs to your coupon.
If you're adding more than just a few, stop here and use the create in bulk button on your Coupons
dashboard.
Rather than adding ASINs one by one, you can upload a spreadsheet with your product information
to add them to your coupon all at once.
If you're adding ASINs individually, search by ASIN or product title to manage
which products and variations appear on your coupon.
Four, select continue to next step.
Five, choose whether you'll be creating a percentage off or money off coupon
and enter the discount amount you'd like to offer your customers.
For more expensive items, we recommend using a money off coupon.
Customers will be able to quickly reference exactly how much they'll be saving
without having to calculate their discount.
Whether you choose percentage off or money off, however,
we recommend creating a coupon that discounts the product by at least 10%.
Six, choose whether you'll allow customers to redeem your coupon once or multiple times.
Seven, enter your budget, which isn't a hard limit and should be used for planning purposes only.
Eight, select continue to next step.
Nine, click title guidelines to review our rules
and then enter your coupon title.
Customers will see this title under the coupon image while they browse the coupon's home page.
We automatically generate the first three words that appear on each of your coupons
based on the discount you entered.
All you have to do is let your customers know what products the savings will apply to.
Ten, choose which Amazon customer type will be eligible to use your coupon.
You can make it available to all customers or only Amazon Prime,
Amazon Student or Amazon Family Members.
Eleven, schedule the duration of your coupon and keep in mind that all coupons expire after 90 days.
To start, we recommend setting a duration of two to three months.
Twelve, select continue to next step.
Thirteen, review your coupon details.
If you notice any errors,
select the numbered circle related to that step to go back and make any necessary updates.
Fourteen, click submit coupon.
If your coupon is approved,
customers will discover it in search results on product detail pages
and on the coupon's home page in the Amazon store.
This concludes our training on how to set up a coupon.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.